

Phone: +961-81972024
asif.k.alam@net.usek.edu.lb
Jdeideh, Matn, Lebanon

Links: GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

PROFILE

A software engineer and computer engineering student with remarkably high grades and various work experience in various sectors. Possess excellent critical thinking and problem-solving skills alongside multilingual capabilities and a love for programming, been working in the field for the past year and keen to tackle challenges at your company.

EDUCATION

Holy Spirit University of Kaslik USEK Sep 2021 - Current

Bachelor's in Computer Engineering

Current GPA: 90.15

GGTA2 Public School Sep 2019 - June 2021

Lebanese Baccalaureate in Life Sciences

Grade: 18.4/20 Ranked 19th in Lebanon.

WORK EXPERIENCE

QWERTY

May 2024 - Now

<u>Freelance</u>

May 2023 - May 2024

Stitches Studio

March 2024 - May 2024

IEEE USEK SB

December 2022 - December 2023

USEK

October 2022 - October 2023

APSAD

October 2021 - February 2022

Lead Engineer

Leading ideation and development at this exciting startup, working on various projects, providing innovative and sustainable solutions based on client needs.

Full stack Developer

Built a diverse and interesting portfolio of projects using the latest technologies and best practices while interacting with clients and corporations.

Full stack Developer

Worked in a SCRUM environment on the Education Basket Systems, using React.js and Nest.js to upgrade and maintain the existing system while writing maintainable and reliable code.

Active Committee Member

Coordinated and organized IEEE events like the SYPLC 2023, while working together to tackle various budget and management problems with different organisations.

Student Representative of the School of Engineering

Actively worked to enhance the student experience at the university. Played a vital role in the exchange rate crisis resolution.

Social Worker

Tracked and managed all ongoing projects at one of the leading NGO in Lebanon.

SKILLS

Next.js	_	Java	
React.js		Tailwind CSS	
Nest.js	-	React Native	
Team Leadership		Database Management	
No-Code Development		Software Engineering	
Agile Development		Python	